The declassified true story of the horse soldiers
12 Strong is a war, drama, action film directed by Nicolai Fuglsig.
A team of special forces head into Afghanistan in the aftermath of the
September 11th attacks in an attempt to dismantle the Taliban.
Mitch Nelson, played by Chris Hemsworth.
Hal Spencer, played by Michael Shannon.
Sam Diller, played by Michael Peña.
General Dostum, played by Navid Negahban.
Ben Milo, played by Trevante Rhodes.
Sean Coffers, played by Geoff Stults.
12 Strong (also known as 12 Strong: The Declassified True Story of the Horse Soldiers) is a 2018
American action-war film directed by Nicolai Fuglsig and written by Ted Tally and Peter Craig.
The film is based on Doug Stanton's non-fiction book Horse
Soldiers, which tells the story of U.S.
Army Special Forces sent to Afghanistan immediately after the
September 11 attacks and up to the fall of Mazar-i-Sharif.
The film stars Chris Hemsworth, Michael Shannon, Michael Peña, Navid Negahban, Trevante Rhodes,
Geoff Stults, Thad Luckinbill, Ben O'Toole, William Fichtner, and Rob Riggle.
Principal photography began in January 2017 in New Mexico.
The film was released in the United States on January 19, 2018, by Warner Bros.
Pictures, in standard and IMAX theaters.
It received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the cast and action but criticized the
by-the-numbers execution and lack of insight of the War in Afghanistan.
The film explores themes of central intelligence agency (cia), based on
novel or book, afghanistan, based on true story, taliban.
The tone is emotional and intense.